hello everyone welcome to the John Caleb
podcast it's me your host Ed and Eddie
I'm happy that you are here this is an
episode with John the Faber it's
wonderful he is a poetically an
externally successful man with a
checkered past he's been a taxi driver a
lawyer a convict an activist a third of
a billionaire a musician an author an
environmentalist a philanthropist and
more the multi-millionaire jail jailbird
owned 27 percent of the PayPal of online
gambling he's worked with grammy-winning
Ward granny me English he's worked with
Grammy winning music producers and
co-founded dsmog.com a Blog dedicated to
exposing
climate misinformation campaigns so yeah
we had a good convo um you can read the
description for more of kind of what we
talked about uh this episode is actually
a bit old this is technically a year and
a half old where it seems kind of crazy
to be posting something that old but I
assure you outside of me mentioning hey
I just moved to Austin four months ago
and me saying this now there's nothing
that that seems to date it um as will be
with these other episodes I have a few
more episodes to post as I've mentioned
on here on these little intros on the
podcast of things that I've recorded and
I'm a bum and so I never posted them and
they've just been sitting waiting to be
edited and I haven't you know brought
them to the Forefront of my time so
anyhow this is the intro I hope
everyone's well uh man I I need to do an
episode where I just kind of like check
in where I just like talk Theo Von style
to the camera and just without me trying
to you know teach you something or
present a guest or you know tell you I
am something that it's so important and
have you listen to me for um way too
long
I should just do an episode where I just
where we just catch up because things
are going good things are going good I'm
out here in Austin still
um uh it's been kind of a few dry months
as far as work and uh events and whatnot
I work in Live Events still
um but uh things are beginning to pick
back up it's kind of the kind of the
case with the winter months in Live
Events but um yeah moving along hanging
out otherwise writing creating a lot
hanging out existing kind of getting a
little more stable reading a lot uh uh
yeah dude anyway we'll get going to the
episode anybody feel free to reach out I
appreciate you listening I hope you're
doing well I hope you're drinking water
I hope you're stretching I hope you're
gaining something from this damn podcast
um
I spend so much my time on this podcast
I really spent a lot of time on this so
I just anytime anybody gains anything
from it I'm like yeah dude I love doing
it so you know I'm gonna keep doing it
but the fact that anybody has any sort
of positive benefit from me Amron and
stammer and
what not it's crazy so anyway here's the
episode I love you
good job hello and welcome to the
junkyard love podcast
[Music]
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
and what age should we learn to have
better conversations with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is well I I heard recording in
progress and I thought holy [__] I'm
late no yeah I always just try to hit
that right at the beginning because I
have had times where I have actually
forgotten until a couple minutes in and
I'm like oh that's that's great I gotta
hit record late so I just always try to
hit it at the beginning so hey John how
are you man very nice to meet you Jacob
I'm pleased to be here this morning are
you um you're in central where
whereabouts are you a man coming to you
from Austin Texas actually oh yeah I
hear a lot about you guys
are you staying healthy yeah yeah I've
been staying pretty healthy I'm pretty
new I'm pretty new to the uh Austin
world I'm uh I've only been here for
about four months oh good for you where
are you from uh originally from
Washington State oh yeah I'm just across
the border from there and uh you ever
hear Salt Spring Island
you guys have you guys have the San
Juans yeah yeah yeah those islands
continue on our side of the border and
like we call them the gulf islands and
I'm on I you know I can if I could if I
climb up the mount you know if I climb
up a hill here I can see San Juans oh
that's cool have you always been there
is that where you were born and raised
uh no I was born in Ontario my dad was a
soldier
um but my mom was raised in Calgary my
dad died when I was about three you know
in an automobile mishap
and my mom moved back to her hometown
Calgary so I spent most of my you know
um developmental years in in Calgary
which is a beautiful city I don't know
if you know much about it but it's um
about
um an hour
about an hour from my high school
parking lot was Banff okay yeah so we
pull into the you know the parking lot
and go okay what's it gonna be school or
bath
right right right
it's a bit like Denver I guess in some
ways you know situated on the Eastern
slopes of the mountains do you see what
I mean by that yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
I do I uh I definitely
I think I prefer I mean I've only been
here for a few months down down in Texas
but I um I definitely realize how much I
really value the weather and everything
over there obviously it's been been hot
over here so it's just kind of a little
turned up but uh just the the beauty of
all the greenery and uh and being able
to have the elevation gain the mountains
it's it's something that you don't you
take it for granted until you're not
around it and you're like oh I kind of
wish that I had some mountains and some
Greenery around me I live in an island
called Salt Spring Island it's about two
and a half hours to Vancouver by ferry
and driving uh but it's about 25 minutes
to downtown Vancouver by float plane for
about 100 bucks
and um so we're you know if you take
float plans into account you know we
reckon that we live in the best
neighborhood in Vancouver we keep a
little apartment downtown Vancouver too
because I have grandchildren there and
you know
it's you know the same old different
story except you know we're Super Lucky
we get to do it we get to do it this way
you know I'm looking I'm looking out
here at the tide coming in and you know
watching Kingfishers and herons uh they
you know serve themselves up
can you imagine it'd be like to be a
like a um you know a heron you just
stand there and you stand and you stand
silent and still and um wait to see what
the universe serves up at your feet
yeah without completely thinking about
it every two seconds about what's about
to happen standing still is so actually
you had I heard you mentioned in a
podcast I was listening to and I think
you said it was a quote from your book
it was like uh I might even jotted it
down oh be still but still be still yet
still be yeah yeah yeah that's uh yeah
we'll talk about it we'll talk a little
bit about that today if you want I'm
yeah well I just know you don't you
don't want to jump into these things
right away because then you don't say
them after the yeah or I guess we are
recording aren't we yeah yeah we're
recording I mean whatever but yeah sure
you have to decide yeah yeah right okay
well then again be still yet still be
that's a big part of um
the things we find when we do that uh is
what joined us together as uh uh equals
the world over yeah yeah okay well let's
uh let's find a way to point towards
that uh be still but yet still be
um so what's your I mean how did you get
so you wrote that you've written books
um you were also talking about how it's
a it's a 100 a hundred dollar plane
that's different than flying uh uh
private jets and whatnot from from your
past you had experience with jets right
yeah I owned one yeah yeah so you owned
a jet so yeah that's a different world
so how about just uh let's start with a
little bit of your bio like kind of
what's what's a little bit of your
background and what kind of LED you into
into writing and advocating for the
things that you do now
well
um
I was raised in the Catholic tradition
and um you know that was in you know I
was born in 1951 so I'm you know
I guess an old guy
I was born and um raised in a Catholic
tradition uh you know in the the the the
biggest take I had on that for the first
half of my life was that I was a rebel
against it
um
um I became an acid head you know I was
like we would uh we'd line up at the
Record Shop to get the new um
Jefferson Airplane 45. okay do you know
what a 45 is final yeah yeah oh yeah I'm
actually a DJ so I I don't use vinyl but
uh but I have been a DJ for 10 years I'm
more of a digital DJ but yes carry on so
and that part of my life I pretty much
laid the good groundwork for all of the
my whole vision of what it means to be a
human being in the universe
um you know it's one it's one thing to
get a glimpse of it's another thing to
actually live it and that's
you know what I've been spending the
rest of my life trying to do is um
um you know real realize and not
realizing the way of coming aware of it
but make real it within myself the
things I understood that I could be when
I was quite young
um you know I don't think I don't think
I've learned anything that is of
fundamental importance in my life since
I was 17 and did a whole bunch too much
acid one day yeah suddenly you realize
what you really are and there's nothing
else that's really gonna going to Trump
that what yeah so you were you were 17
when you started doing lse acid
uh I I might I might have been at the
very end of 16. do you ever think about
how if you had never done it especially
at a young age how different your life
would be like it would it would be just
I I used to imagine utterly different
but I'm not so sure anymore you know
there are lots of people who have um you
know uh
I don't I don't hope this doesn't sound
too Preposterous but you know to why
there's lots of people who wound up more
or less where I have who've never done
anything like that in their life
there's lots of there are lots of ways
we can um awaken that
yeah I know that miracle that dwells
within us all I love it and then and
that's one of them Neil Young in one of
his songs she says you know when when
the aimless blade of Silence of science
crashed the Pearly Gates
and so it was like you know just by
blind luck one day somebody eat some air
gut fungus the next thing you knew they
realized they were you know Godly
yeah yeah have you ever uh have you ever
looked into the stone date Theory at all
have you ever heard of that I have heard
I don't know much about it though tell
me oh man I think that I've butchered it
on this podcast more than once but uh I
learned about it from Terence McKenna
talking about it essentially
um when we were Apes it's kind of a
theory of how Consciousness may have
developed or like how our language and
in the Linguistics developed came out of
the trees as Apes we started looking for
food foraging and we started flipping
over cow pies following cow pies we
started finding uh these mushrooms and
and obviously we don't have a I don't
know if in this scenario we have totally
a conscious mind at that point but it
did make us better at hunting it made
our visual Acuity better it made us a
better Community I think Terence McKenna
talks about how it uh it likely led to a
lot of like orgiastic communities and so
that brought brought more people
together expanded so just kind of like
made culture this thing from apes
hopping out of trees and finding cell
Simons and Simon mushroom and just
keeping following that
um you'll definitely have to look up
Stone Dave Theory after this yeah no I I
show you guys now of it but I've made
notes about it before but never yeah
thanks for the encouragement I will
follow up on that now
yeah yeah yeah I'm reading a book now
about uh what's called uh the
immortality key Ryan uh um yeah I can
never say his last name I didn't get
through that
um it's it's very dense and but it's
very very profound
um I'm probably like halfway through it
what do you think so far oh it's
beautiful I mean that it's too bad the
guy didn't you know fall off the wagon
and actually try it once I know I'm
waiting for him too I'm waiting for like
this YouTube video of him like all right
last night I did acid
yeah I don't I'm a little bit reluctant
to pitch it because um
it's um it can be um I don't I'm sure
you've read it in a book but it can be a
disturbing place to go and we need to be
well prepared for it and um and you know
it's not it
um it depends on what you bring to the
party
right and if if we still have issues
with our you know mum
show their face yeah they'll definitely
uh stare us down in the moment when we
want it the least and you know it's a
but on the other hand it's a profoundly
uh
powerful
mechanism for getting to know ourselves
the way we really are
you know there's a at the end of my book
uh I too quote I quote two people
throughout my book that are not in
fashion anymore one of them is Adam
Smith and the other one is Jesus of
Nazareth and they were two actually very
very stoned [__]
[Laughter]
but I'm going to read you something
um Jesus said there's a guy named Thomas
who the Gospel of Thomas has never been
embraced by the Catholic church but it's
a very very Stone thing and I and I I
just love it I love you know I was I've
been thinking about doing you know a
book on my interpretations of what those
very mysterious things that he said but
he is said by Thomas to have said
let him who seeks continue seeking until
he finds
when he finds he will become troubled
when he becomes troubled he will be
astonished and he will rule over the awe
so kids don't drop acid until you're
ready to be troubled
but know that you know when we realize
the fundamental things about ourselves
we realize you know among other things
how uh
um
thoughtless we've been to so many others
in the world here we are you know the um
uh top 20 of the world we're more or
less demographically socio-economically
um taking for granted um things that
would be utterly miraculous to you know
the starving lady in Sudan
and um we take them utterly for granted
uh without thinking for a moment
um if we
have actually if if there's if there are
dues to pay for that kind of beauty that
we experience in our in the life we take
for granted here in Western Society
you know you might have heard me say
yeah I want you know you uh
as many times as you've hacked up the
the uh who is it the naked ignore what's
the ape the uh oh Stone Dave's the stone
date yes
I've hacked up this one but
um
Freedom that you know the freedom the
freedom that we enjoy in our society
um that we've you know we've been told
since we were children that it was you
know it comes at a cost and the cost is
the highest cost uh of course you know
what they meant was giving your life
fighting in Wars to protect Freedom
um and uh that it doesn't make that much
sense to me because the um you know
first of all maybe one in 250 000 people
die
or I don't I don't really know how many
I mean it is everybody else gets it for
free that didn't make sense for me but
so I started to think about it more and
um there is a cost for freedom and I
think the cost is that we have to um
uh strive every day to assure that we're
on the track of providing to all others
who are less fortunate us the same
benefits that we take for granted in our
life every day and if we do that every
day then we've earned our freedom but if
we do not you know the way the way in
that same book that says Be Still yet
still be uh it says those who are
content with the benefits of freedom but
careless of what other is less fortunate
um must endure have not earned her
freedom uh we've only taken liberties
we're Taking Liberties like that
wow okay so so paying the price of
freedom is to strive to make sure that
every you know the 80 in the world that
don't enjoy what you and I are enjoying
right now are getting closer to enjoying
them all of them themselves you know
wouldn't it be the when the Declaration
of Independence all men are created
equal first of all you know quaintly
they called people men we think I think
they meant people actually they they
really did mean white men but we know
now
we know now that uh it it is quite quite
a bit Also may I say this broader than
that yeah yeah
um um hey do we but it does mean all it
does mean all and now on all means
everybody everywhere I can read and I'd
like to talk about that more if you feel
like it yeah yeah definitely um I I was
just I mean down that same road I was
kind of thinking about I've actually
recently been kind of rethinking what
Freedom means to me lately
um and not not in this like you know
running around the parking lot with an
American flag I'm not trying to like
talk about like that it just um I I had
a podcast guess uh his name was Bradley
and he was talking about
um like how much he values freedom and
like he's like freedom of time Freedom
of Choice
um it the way that he broke down the
word freedom and what it really means I
started to realize oh I actually do
value that very much and I was thinking
also
um at a young age I was very drawn to
like the rebels of music you know rock
and I was a warped tour for me which
isn't that like that edgy I guess but um
just all these artists who were
who were they're breaking things they
were they were they were on stage saying
things into the mic then I'm like you're
allowed you're allowed to say that and
it's like oh yeah that's that's what
this thing is we are allowed to say that
oh yeah like we're not supposed to just
listen for what's right and then we like
lean into what we think is is
so
Freedom what does it mean
like you you've also had you know
Financial Freedom so do you think that
your definition of freedom or your
internal like um dialogue when it comes
to the word Freedom has changed since
when you were a younger kid and now and
maybe maybe even like what does freedom
really mean mean to you now
yeah I I'm sure it has changed but
essentially it comes to the same thing I
just realized more things about it the
the the the the things that we take for
granted about Freedom have have
implications and it's the implications
and I've been you know embracing and you
know what for grappling with and then
embracing the um
I think all of the things that we enjoy
in our day-to-day life in you know the
West we call it the West I don't know
what to call it you know
um the society created by white
patriarchy
I think all of the things that we take
for granted in that Society are the key
key elements of Freedom let me go
through them
um security and integrity of the person
respect of the person uh access to
reasonable access to food clothing and
shelter
access to the tools of self-improvement
into Health Access to Basic Finance and
justice
and access to a healthy environment
so we in our society we talk about some
of those things but not all of them
but we do take them all for granted more
or less and uh and
you know I think we should because I
think they are the basic elements of
freedom and we if we if we Proclaim that
we are Defenders of Freedom we should
understand it but I think that you know
those elements in our society are you
know the fruit of freedom
that you know the juice is worth the
squeeze does that ring a bell
it's something I think I heard you say
um
the uh and
you know
if we if we are entitled to them and I
think we are you know I think we're
properly entitled to those things then
the question becomes well if we are or
why what distinguishes us that we're
entitled to them but others are not and
that's a very very difficult um
question to answer and the best I can do
with it is there is no this there's
nothing to distinguish us you know us in
this in the um you know the starving
people in the deserts of uh
in Somalia you know they um
we all have the same you know capacity
to dream and the same capacity
capacity to be disappointed
and
those
um
those those are the things I think that
make us
responsible to go out and deliver what
has befallen us to all of all others as
well because we had because of being
being compassionate beings we understand
that they have the same capacity to be
disappointed as we do and if we're in
their position we would be [__] well
disappointed that's for sure you know it
would be you know we would be suicidal
if we lived in uh
many of us would be because it just
could not bear it and um
no I and I don't think this is something
that's going to change in my lifetime I
don't know how much time I got left but
a lot less than you do and I was
thinking the other day you know you know
a long time well I don't I think it was
a short time from 1969 until today you
know I think
for whatever reason that time frame was
real fast for me yeah and so if that you
know if that if that if that's a short
time imagine how short the time is that
I have left in this world because I sure
don't have 50 years left right yeah so
um but I'd like to uh if if I if I leave
a legacy what I'd like it to be is
impress people with the responsibilities
that come with freedom the one thing
that's really changed for me about
freedom is understand I hated the word
responsibility when I was a kid because
I kind of thought that you know
responsibility wasn't that just what
it's not you know it's not just you know
it's why should we make it a duty it's
what responsibilities are things that
compassionate people will think of
themselves anyways and you know look
after her but
um
I've become too I've come to embrace the
idea of responsibility that the
responsibilities of Freedom
um are um ignored by by many in our
society and uh you know they are content
with what Freedom has dropped in their
lap and uh and quite thoughtless about
other people in the world who um must
endure
uh with almost infinitely less
than we have right like nothing and yeah
and so and um it's a it's a huge Joy
it's a tall order it's very audacious
and I don't expect really people to um
uh fall for this quickly because my
experiences is that they don't but
um you know when we'll look at it this
way I we spoke of Adam Smith and uh uh
and before and you know John Stewart
Mill was a buddy of his and they those
guys were sort of the initiators of the
um
uh the concept that individuals have
certain uh are entitled to certain
levels of respect and you know rights
and what have you
and you know here we are 250 years later
Jacob and uh you know about 10 of the
people on the planet actually buy that
now so you know and things happen much
more quickly now so my idea is that you
know if um but you know I already know
people have not embraced my ideas
rapidly
um it would be a wonderful thing you
know at some you know when I'm you know
floating around on one of those clouds
up there with Van Gogh and the rest of
them you know um the the uh to to
realize that uh you know people were
saying you know that your grandfather he
actually he had a hold of something
there
that's a nice thing to start to strive
for I like that yeah yeah it's like that
what's the analogy where you uh you you
plant seeds not so you can
it's basically planting a tree so your
grandchildren can sit in the shade you
know and I think that's that's a great
mindset you know where our culture now
you know especially with young people
and I don't know if it's a phase or if
it's just something like we're just
seeing a lot but it's very like uh we're
instant gratification we want to see our
results now we don't seem to think much
like we think out of like this week or
next week or this year or whatever but
we don't really be able to we don't
really seem to think long term of our of
our actions and reactions we kind of
like assume that some you know magic uh
Steward pilot has has control the whole
ship and you know someone is steering
Earth in the right direction and we're
gonna be fine we're just gonna do what
we want but there is I think uh
responsibility again of of really trying
to think of like how our actions and
what we do and what we plan on doing and
what we talk about and what we plan on
talking about
um affects the next Generations like we
we must think in that way or it's kind
of kind of it's I mean it seems game
over if not you know we're not gonna
We're Not Gonna Last incredibly long if
we don't
um think about the future once in a
while you know
well and and plan how it should be right
plan how it might be gonna let it happen
yeah we should we should we should
imagine what what a a the future we
would yearn for looks like and um and
some of us will yearn for um you know
Yachts filled with hookers
others of us will have
um no uh you know either by experience
or by having read it in a book that
um that wears very very thin very very
quickly yeah you know those things you
know I'd uh
I you know I had two houses on on the
beach in Malibu and I had you know at
the same time and I had closets full of
clothes that you know still had price
tags on them and you know that sort of
thing cars cars that I didn't even have
license plates on yet yeah and um
and all your problems weren't solved
yeah you know you'd think but um
very quick I I was fortunate when you
know when I came to wealth because I was
you know I was you know in my 50s uh and
um so I had some
opportunity to consider what it really
means you know I spent most of my life
thinking that you know you know if if a
guy's Rich he's probably a dick and then
I became to the point well you know uh
just because he's Rich he might not be a
dick I don't know what else he does with
his time and his money that sort of
thing
um eventually you know I've come to the
view that
um
you know wealth is going to be super
important to accomplish all the things
that I've got in mind first
uh but you know just I was but to
complete the idea we were talking about
um
very quickly I got to the point where
you know buying uh a new you know Alpena
Roadster was um
you know not that big of a thrill
anymore and I found it became evident to
me that you know the the the the the the
the thing that got me the most high was
sharing that with others so I would take
you know my friend family friends and
take their kids to Rodeo Drive and start
making piles in all the stores and you
know wind up spending like thirty
thousand dollars on stuff for for you
know the kids in the family and you know
and just and they and you know people
just loved that so much and Jacob the
the dividends of that you know the
dividends of that kind of it's not it's
not you know it's kind of ill-conceived
generosity but still it's generosity
um are just magnificent they'll last
forever you know people think that you
know the gratitude that comes from
giving people that cereal is a way
bigger Rush than you know hiding another
million under a rock somewhere you know
stuffing it under a mountain somewhere
and calling it yours
that's one of the things I like to tell
people that you know hoarding hoarding
is the wanking of wealth right but it's
that it lasts about that long you know
then you have to work some more and then
it lasts about that long but you know
the making love of wealth is the sharing
of it and you know the the mysterious
astonishing thing about that is that
when we do that we don't wind up with
less we wind up with much much more and
I'm not talking just about more in our
hearts but I am talking about that too I
think as we develop people the world
over in the third world we called it
when I was a young guy I don't know what
they call it now but you know the places
you know if if we develop those Human
Resources so those people can look look
after themselves well
um they become more productive and I
remember productivity used to be a word
annoying time but you know proactive
people create wealth and uh you know I
talked to some you know pretty
right-wing guys you know um uh about
about this but they agreed with me that
um well theoretically is infinite and
you know when when we improved the human
resources that are uh the 80 of the
world that are not completely
um uh
tuned up as they could be to be pulling
on the oars right when we do do that the
world is going to be so much more
wealthy and all these guys who think
that you know hoarding and
stuffing all their [__] in the vault is
um make it's an improvement are going to
be surprised to find out that actually
they're going to be living in a world
full of rich people and nobody wants
their money anymore they've got their
own and you can you know if you you
don't have to share much of it to make
that happen either you know I really
like Elizabeth Warren's idea of the
wealth taxes was it is a brilliant idea
taxing uh what does it uh Estates that
are have a value of about 50 million
dollars and you only tax them on the
month the amount of that 50 million
dollars and then there's another tax
rate for people with a billion dollars
and you know but and if if we
implemented something like that
um there would be you know free daycare
free uh Health Care Free education
um you know uh for for everybody you
know guaranteed annual income for
everybody in on the planet you know we
would be able to do that and um and when
you do that it's a different world you
have a world where you know um as I'm
you know as I like to say you know when
when were Janice with when we're
generous with people they don't bust our
balls
you know and it can't cost more than the
military costs right no not much right
and yeah not exactly and so
um
and then we'll still need military or
something like it one of the biggest
here's the most difficult part of my
theory Jacob the
um
we have to use Force we have to use
Force sometimes when it happens inside
our borders and the police use it to
stop a rape or an extortion or something
like that terrorist activity we're quite
we're quite calm about it I mean
actually we require it we demand it but
when it's across the board we go oh no
no that's War we have again we can't
have responsibility for those clitorises
of the young girls and you know um Sudan
you know no we should you know that's
not that that that's you know
jurisdiction we don't have a
jurisdiction well we have to get over
that one of the things that I like to
talk about is how little we know you
know man imagine how much we learned uh
in the last hundred years
yeah I mean even like 20 years with the
internet and everything
well sure in the last 20 years the last
50 years yeah but pick your number and
and extrapolate that into the next
hundred
yeah that's how much we don't know now
extrapolate out of the next thousand
that's how much we don't know now
and we think we know that we can't go
help that young girl in Somalia because
she's going to get her [__] slashed off
with a ripped off old tin can top
um you know
I know that doesn't sit well with me
anymore that you know some some ideas
like jurisdiction uh or something
sovereignty uh forces us to accept that
and I you know I think among the things
we we don't know that we're going to be
learning and I think I'll help quite
quickly is that we actually do have a
responsibility to that young woman and
um uh and I'm encouraging people to
start thinking about that right now
I describe a little bit in my book about
how I think things like that would work
but sovereignty is one of the lamest
excuses we've ever had for not helping
people for for not fulfilling the costs
of our freedom by helping those people
in Somalia what do you mean by
sovereignty in this situation what well
we're not allowed to go in there and
like force the government there to do
stuff you know we we can't because
they're they're a sovereign government
and they say get out they take your nose
out of our domestic policy well their
domestic policy as I own this country
and it's all mine so [__] you yeah yeah
right I mean and then we have to okay
fair enough you know that sovereignty
man you know but no you know so we have
to you know we have to so I'm talking
about this in the sense of the things
that we don't know yet we take for
granted that sovereignty is um
um a limitation Upon Our capacity to
help others and I think we have to
reconsider that there's really good
reason to suspect that we
ought to honor sovereignty for some
things but not those you know if they're
if there are um
if if there are uh
catastrophic breaches of Human Rights uh
occurring
um sovereignty cannot be a defense for
that kind of behavior so we have to go
out and force those people too to get
into line and we have to do it by
protecting the people that are under
their uh spell and uh and corralling the
people who are perpetrating these kinds
of atrocities and and it's not it's not
it's not it's not a matter of taste or
preference it's a responsibility we have
to do that
yeah it's you know what I was thinking
about John is like
I I don't know if this is like a
deflection maybe it's a deflection
um but but I think a lot of times I feel
almost crippled by all the things that I
should be doing that all the things that
like I wish my life was
um at least directing towards or or
helping out I mean you you can go on
Tick Tock or Instagram or YouTube or any
of these you know the internet is is
vast for sure it's a kind of the fungal
network of our of our planet in a sense
so we're able to see I mean we can watch
videos of these horrific things
happening
um we're able to know about all these
Downstream effects of all of our actions
like we could buy a a tomato at the
supermarket but we don't realize that
the downstream effects of it being
shipped over to us like someone was paid
three bucks an hour and then the person
who picked it was paid a dollar fifty an
hour and they don't have shoes there's
all these like things that it just seems
so overwhelming to try to try to
concentrate on how do I
how do I do good how do I um you know
try to lean into these things because
I'm also like I I'm still trying to take
take care of myself I'm still trying to
like all right I don't even feel like I
have my career set out I don't feel like
I'm I'm face it I have all my own [__]
how do I
how do I care about that and then also
care about care about everything else
like what's what's the balance of of not
being drowned by by too much um
stuff you know responsibility of the
responsibilities of Freedom you know the
responsibilities to strive to share
Freedom true Freedom you know um is uh
uh
uh it is it is a individual
responsibility we should each strive to
do it in all the ways that we can in our
even if it's just by telling people to
read my book
awareness this helps but um there's also
a collective responsibility and we
should be doing all of those things
International Development as a as a as a
collective not as individual yes you
have to you know we have to worry about
the two for tomato growers in Mexico but
we we have influence over Mexico and and
they're um you know their rapacious uh
farmers who underpay their workers you
know
um we have influence over them and we
don't exercise it as much as we could
and um you know why why is Vladimir
Putin using Western Banks
why is his billions
in Europe
and New York
because why do we let him why do we let
him do that we don't have like Shell
station or Kellogg's or some so one of
these corporations is being benefited by
it I'm sure yeah well it's it's part of
our Capital base it's part of what makes
us privileged just to have that capital
in our base right but we don't have to
we we we we can put the squeeze on uh uh
we can put the squeeze on guys like
Putin out there in the world you know
and the Koch brothers and the rest of
those we can put the squeeze on them you
know and then
the juice is worth the squeeze there you
go let me tell you this
constitutional democracy has created the
two most powerful tools ever invented by
our species to control the selfish
wealthy
they are the powers to tax and the
powers to regulate
and the worst thing that we can do in
the world right now is
discourage young people from becoming
involved in constitutionally democratic
governments say government can never do
anything right every time they tax you
they're just stealing from your pocket
no that's wrong that's what the selfish
wealth they want you to think because
they want you all to turn your backs on
government they want you to not vote but
the one thing they do every time all of
them every damn one of them shows up and
they vote and all of their minions vote
too and they don't and they only get you
know they only have like 30 percent 35
percent of America but they own it
they're running America because they
know what to do with that 35 percent
they show up if the 65 percent showed up
they'd be [__] because they would be
seizing they were the 65 would be
seizing the levers of constitutional
democracy
uh of the democratic power
and they would be utilizing the powers
to tax and the powers to regulate to end
what those guys do
and you know what it will not be the end
of wealth it'll only be the end of
wealth for them
sometimes sometimes it feels like we
have to
like in in order to feel like
we're still
playing their game it feels it feels
like
um and I guess I'm you know kind of
inadvertently speaking on um uh like
like the people who feel frustrated by
the government who think how the
government doesn't do anything right or
um my vote is worthless or whatever the
thought is I think that's kind of like
where I'm where I'm stemming from but
it's uh it feels to me and tell me what
you think about this
it feels like we need like a like a
democracy 2.0 like a like a constitution
uh like upgrade or uh uh and these
things are great like like I'm not the
type to like burn it let's not burn it
all down and see what we have there From
the Ashes like definitely not but it
does feel like we we need some sort of
overhaul because there is so many like
you said you know 65
um there's just so many I I don't think
I'm alone when I say that I don't know
who to trust I don't know what the
government's telling me if it's true you
know in in the news stations have made
it more more intense and more confusing
um it's it it's yeah I I don't know do
what what's the how do we actually make
this change like how would you actually
see it happen obviously it's not going
to be an overnight thing but do you
think there has to be some sort of um I
mean I hope not war but some sort of
like defining moment of change or
anything or is this a gradual we just
start working towards it or
five percent more Americans need to go
out and vote and vote against selfish
wealthy
that's all and the whole thing will
change you know the the and all that you
know if we're on a cusp now and you know
I'm a Canadian but and bless your hearts
for allowing me to comment on what's
going on in your country but you do call
yourselves the leader of the world so we
have an interest in what you do
yeah right but I hope so you know um all
of the things that are giving the
selfish wealthy their thumb on the
weight on this on the scales of
constitutional democracy uh the
gerrymandering the voter suppression uh
the keeping people ignorant by not
providing them with education uh
creating people who are disabled as to
reading between the lines they actually
read the lines and believes them rather
than can you approach them with this
with a sense of Health criticism
um you know um
all it all it will take is for the 65 in
in America to come out and support
people who will
who who wish
to
[Music]
um manage the selfish wealthy
and I'm not talking about putting an end
to anybody all I'm talking about is
making sure that those people pay their
fair share
right and that they follow the rules
they don't get to dump mercury into Love
Canal and say I thought it was a free
country I thought this was a free
country yeah no
they have to and and it and back to the
topic of the moment and that is
we're only about five or six or seven
percent of the electorate in America
away from watching all of that tumble
you know all it takes is all it will
take is one federal law
to make gerrymandering illegal
can you can you define gerrymandering
for me Jerry mattingers was when you is
it when you [__] with the boundaries of
the cons of the the
congressional districts or the you know
the uh um and they um
you know what so what you do is if
you've got a a a in you know in town
you've got this concentration of
liberals right instead of having like
you know big uh three three seats in in
town they're filled with liberals what
you do is you take this you draw the
seats so there's a great big swash of
out in the country where there's
conservatives and then take them into
town and take down about you know uh
about a quarter of the Liberals and put
them out in in a writing that's mostly
you know uh people out in the country
who are more conservative
um so you tilt the scales that way with
gerrymandering it's something that you
know the your your Supreme Court just
recently said we have no interest in
this because it's a state matter but um
I I think that's fundamentally
um ill-conceived uh you know they're
they're they're they're they're messing
with
the balance of the balance of voting
yeah you know so by gerrymandering and
all of the other you know by and they do
do that you hear about redistricting all
the time that's what they're talking
about when you're talking about
redistricting they're talking about
changing the districts so that the guys
in power can have a better advantage
next time that's what they're talking
about that's not fair and if America
wants to be fair they have to you know
and you know the that that politically
based redistricting when they do
the selfish power are going to the
selfish wealthy are going to lose their
um unequal uh grip upon the levers of
constitutional democracy and the powers
to attacks and regularly so we're just
that close to it that's the beautiful
thing about constitutional democracy you
just have to make sure that the majority
actually have a say and when you know
when you do when we do that then um you
know the uh this uh imbalanced uh uh
influence that wealth has over the
system can be eradicated but you know
it's not going to be it's not going to
be happening as long as the wealthy guys
own the Mitch McConnells and keep
sending them back
and that's what's going on you know you
got this what's this kind of the who's
this you know the
governor in Florida what the hell is his
name he wants to give you a fine if you
tell people to put on a mask I don't
want to say his name because he doesn't
you know he that's what he's looking for
attention all right yeah yeah he wants
to be the click bait so he's popular
that's how everybody's everybody wants
clout that's what everybody's doing
lately we even have donors and yeah it's
actually uh you know it's it's it's a
silly thing because it's you're thinking
of like oh you so you're you live in LA
and you're trying to get known so you
can be an actor or whatever it is but
it's like this clout thing this this
recognition this want for fame this want
to be noticed is is really like uh uh
jamming up the the the the drainage
system system of of
of our discourse you know yeah yeah yeah
no we're closer than we think to um to
solving these problems and we just but
you know turning our backs on
constitutional democracy is exactly the
wrong direction to go in it's
repurposing it it's a poor carbon Monroe
blames his tools right hey yeah yeah
right yeah yeah well these these people
are blaming government and not the
carpenter yeah right and they're not
coming up with Solutions either it's
like if you have a problem don't just
complain about it and say oh I've I've
got to sit with it you've got to be
coming up with Solutions because it's
all it's a wee situation it's a US
versus the problem you know exactly let
me let me go on just a wee bit about you
know that's a poor carpenter yeah it's a
poor carpenter who blames the tools
it's a poor board
it's a poor boy how come I'm so white
all of a sudden it's
lighting yeah it's a poor board
that
blames a hammer for getting nailed
it's not the hammer it's the it's the
carpenter it's that's doing the nailing
so we have to we have to stop being
angry at the tool at the government and
we have to start being angry at the guys
who are wielding the Hammers and and
change them it's time you know it's it's
time to change the batter man yeah hey
hell yeah hell yeah uh I I what I see a
lot with uh I think I I've run a lot of
things through the internet and social
media I'm very interested in how
um the internet and social media and our
new systems change change who we are as
humans and and really influence us um
very fascinated by that I think that
they're playing us all right though you
know wrong but but they know what
they're doing you know that they they
have all this psychology on on how we
interact basically they're instead of us
projecting our anger at them and these
systems that need to change and these
people that need to get out of their
chair because it's time for for
something new right now
um they they make us project that anger
at one another they're like hey you're
either you're either red or you're blue
or you're this or you're that and those
are your enemies remember if you're the
good guys this is what you are okay that
feels good but here's the bad guys
here's where they are they're over there
go get them and that's precisely right
that's for sure you know the power of
propaganda is the misinformation
although that's one of the effects of it
uh the power of propaganda is that all
the misinformation that propaganda
um pitches us uh creates
um a lack of confidence that anything at
all works and and then we just turn our
backs on it and then
man
those 35 show up and they get it all
yeah because that's the way
constitutional democracy works if I was
Vladimir Putin and I wanted to wreck
America
what I would do is make sure that young
people turned their backs on government
um if I was Vladimir Putin and I wanted
to really really [__] the West what I
would do is I would promote uh you know
uh voter fraud
anti-vax
and uh you know uh
White lives matter yeah yeah right and
I'd be pushing those things for all it's
worth on on on on you so and you know
what yeah on social media you know what
I think Vladimir Putin's just as smart
as I am
and he's got and he's got the Machinery
set up to do it if he's not doing it
he's an idiot but he's I don't he's he's
not an idiot and he's doing it when you
know when Mueller told us that he was
messing with the elections that's what
he is doing he's absolutely soaking
social media with you know propaganda
that's designed to destroy our faith in
the in the
you know in uh our system of
constitutional democracy you know he's
doing very well at it and I think right
next to it it's uh the possibility of
conversating out of it is also kind of
kind of um I love that idea yeah it's
it's a because it's a very as you're
telling me as you're as you like named
off those three things I was thinking
about how difficult it is to have
regular discourse around these things
nowadays because there's so much extra
with them and there's these weird little
everyone gets uncomfortable and they're
like oh oh I hope they know that I'm
that I I love black people so make sure
I say this thing you know it's it it
strikes us with this very uncomfortable
weird thing and we act like Knuckleheads
um and and there's so much logic that's
right beneath beneath the surface and I
I don't know John I'm excited for us to
uh I I think I I did a good um session
with one of my good friends
um on cancel culture and we're basically
just like what is cancer culture like
why is it important why is it at the
Forefront why are we talking about it
and we kind of came to the end we're
like it's it's dumb like why are we
spending so much time focusing on it why
are we we're kind of talking about like
the pop culture side of of cancer
culture but um it's uh our conversations
are kind of being
taken from us in a strange sense
um so we need to be able to to have the
discourse about it I forgot exactly the
point that I was trying to make on that
but uh I think it is important that we
have discourse around these things and
not be afraid to to to speak on them and
figure out what we really think about
what we really mean what really are
trying to say here
one of the uh one of the things I picked
up on this podcasting was the gentleman
who used the phrase um uh
uh
thoughtful management of attention
uh no it's not thoughtful it's like uh
skilled management of attention and and
what it means is that you know our day
our minds are filled daily with all of
the things okay you've got another video
two you go to this afternoon so I got to
get through then I gotta you know finish
my take the clothes out of the dryer
yeah Peter's coming over for supper in
the weekend he's vegan and he only
drinks white wine and there's got to be
at least you know I got the golf club oh
geez I forgot the accountants calling
all these things keep and you know they
storm us all day long and and um
often that stuff is subjects of
responsibility and so we should you know
by all means be paying attention to them
so I'm not just I'm not dissing all of
those things that come into our minds
because most of them are important what
I am going to say though is at certain
times during the day we have to realize
that those thoughts are stampeding us
and they always will be and we have to
give ourselves the breadth to
um
treat them well that's what they are
they're uninvited guests they're people
who came and knocked on the door without
phoning first they're clients that don't
have an appointment and they show up and
they want to take over and we let them
so but for half an hour every day people
I want us to just decide no not now
those are important things I'm going to
deal with them in half an hour but for
right now I'm just going to shut all of
that down I'm going to sit here and be
quiet and see okay the part of us that
dreams at night Jacob
the part of us that dreams at night does
not go to sleep in the daytime
prayers and dreams at night is there
with us all the time and what I like
people to consider is to sit quietly and
see what that part of us wants to do
with the day right now with all the
things these things I feel inside the
things that are you know that dull ache
where does that come from I feel so
happy but I'm not sure why you know but
so
no stop working that the
responsibilities and the appointments
and all of those things push them away
like their you know clients without an
appointment and every time we do that
that part of us that dreams at night
that still awake in the daytime
starts to astonish us with amazing
understandings and solutions and you
know new New Visions to strive for and
you know and if we do that every time we
do that it's utterly refreshing you know
we were talking before about you know uh
do you have to take acid no you just
have to shut up and let this dreamer
that dwells within us be free for a
moment
and you don't you don't you know and
it's not disregarding the things it's
skilled management of attention paying
attention selecting those things that
are actually uh both important and
urgent but if they're not both of those
things they can wait till later yeah
yeah well I think that we're we're also
incessively thinking all the time so so
in depth that we don't even realize it I
got into meditation uh three years ago I
had a bunch of uh like mental health and
depression and suicidal thoughts and all
the stuff that that really just uh it
just like hit a peaking point and I kind
of had like I gotta do something so I
started learning about my mind I started
learning about what's going on I started
meditating and doing yoga and uh I mean
the difference between how my you know
interior daily cognition Works versus
how it used to work me being completely
just wound up in all the thoughts of
what I think I am and what I'm thinking
about and realizing that you can sit
there and observe those things and watch
them go by just like you can hear sounds
and whatnot uh it's it's it's profound I
think so many people would benefit from
even realizing that you're not you're
not the thinker of your thoughts you're
the The Observer you're the the
conscious awareness of of all this so uh
what do you do you have a do you have
like a a sturdy meditation practice or
do you do you just have you kind of like
learned through the years of of kind of
how to step outside of yourself and just
take that you know 30 minutes of time to
just be and exist is this a yes a
structured thing that you do or yes
foreign
when I was young I I signed up for
Transcendental Meditation I was around
maybe 19 or 20 it was after
um you know about three years of the
world's Championship Acid Trip you know
one day Jim and I did 20 hits acid each
nice and it was you build up to it you
know you do kids please don't pay
attention to this okay
you know if you do if you do one today
you have to do two tomorrow and four the
next day right but
um
so
where was I going with this meditation
yeah
um the um
the the place that that takes us
um uh is the place that we go when we be
still yet still be
that's one of the aphorisms from my book
that you've noticed be still yet still
be and I think it means you know to like
wake up but pay attention you know wake
up wake up and and pay attention it's
not you know it's not like grasping a
bunch of details and starting to work
them out again no it's just be awake for
a moment oh there goes a kingfisher
that's a magic moment right and live it
and feel it and it takes us to a place
so I Transit I did Transcendental
Meditation and you know it was a bit um
it was very very helpful for me because
it helped me understand uh the part
about emptying or emptying our busy
little mind for a moment and seeing what
else is there uh and uh but um
they didn't like us smoking pot and I
couldn't get that I didn't know what
what the heck's wrong with that I mean
how can that get weed and Transcendental
Meditation are holding hands man those
are awesome together well they yeah
exactly that's right but they used to
tell us not so I went on with that but I
still use that technique to meditate but
I don't have a practice of doing that
every day but it has come to the point
for me where I honor at every
opportunity that I get you don't have to
do it for 20 minutes either you can do
it for at every stop late
and every go late isn't that interesting
how you're um I mean for me that's kind
of how it was my you start realizing you
can be kind of every time you notice
throughout your day even if it's a
hundred times those are all benefits
those are all positives like oh I just
noticed that I was lost in my thought
okay I'll just return back to being
present you know glimpses have been late
they're all little glimpses of
Enlightenment yes sir when everything
and whenever that stuff bubbles up
inside us and it's one of the things I
say at the beginning of my book is you
know that people thought it was sorry my
life was so exciting you know who who
has a third of a trillion a billion
dollars 30 billion dollars who has you
know that I you know we hit your folk
your folks don't know this but you know
I I was fortunate we had you know um a
grand slam home run in seven yeah you
know on the internet and started a
business that was sort of like PayPal of
online gambling and um it's called net
teller we started that in 2000 and 2003
went public under London Stock Exchange
in by 2005
um you know it had a market cap of
around uh two billion dollars and I
owned about 27 of that wow man awesome
cool I managed to pull some of that off
the table but the um
uh
the thing that is the most precious to
me in my life
isn't that and the thing that is the
most precious to me in my whole life
uh has fallen into my lap no more than
it has into everybody's
and that thing is this being a conscious
being in the universe we are the
universe's vessels of consciousness and
that is like
immeasurably astonishing
that this came to us and we just
disregard it you know but but that and
and that's in you and I and it's in you
know the the um the starving lady and
and the dying baby in her arms all have
that Consciousness within them within us
and you know when we realize that all we
have to do to access that is just shut
up and be quiet and close down this
faucet of
static that comes in you know our little
busy little mind yeah
um and and and and let that magic
um soothe us and entertain us and solve
all our problems it's like having the
most powerful computer
that anybody could ever manage free
right behind our eyes you don't even
have to you don't even have to touch
that chip in our ear to make it happen
it's like there all the time it's our
default operating system if we just shut
up like you said
and so
um it's a it's it's a wonderful thing to
be wealthy uh but it gave me an
opportunity to consider the um
the the responsibilities of wealth are
very much like the responsibilities of
Freedom wealth and freedom are very
similar
right but the responsibilities of wealth
are to uh they're the same to try our
hardest to assure that those uh
those uh
wonderful benefits are available to as
many others as possible too because
everybody else is entitled to it as much
as I ever was I you know how can you be
entitled to a third of a billion dollars
yeah I earned it man no you didn't
you were you SFA right but um so be
generous Rich guys just a little bit
generous just two percent generous
and all the world will love you and
they'll come and buy your Runners
yeah and they'll all look cool when
they're dancing to your songs and
they'll be watching your movies on TV
you'll be allowing them to make their
own content it's not going to cost much
a guy pointed out to me Joe devoskin
said you know this this little tool in
my hand
it's it has more production power and
better production value than the whole
of Rockefeller Center did in 1970.
and everybody's got it moreover Jacob
it's got all the knowledge more than all
the knowledge that appears in every
University Library on the planet mm-hmm
so all of that knowledge the cumulative
knowledge of our species is now
available to everybody
in the Sahara Desert yeah it's all they
have profound things that's ever
happened to humanity and so and all we
all we have to do is provide a little
bit of guidance to those people not so
that they'll go out and buy our Hummers
no that's not what we want what we want
is for them to be able to do cartoons
and or write books or you know write
little love stories or you know do
little films or whatever it is and you
know make a living for themselves in
their own community and improve improve
their home their their own Human
Resources we if we you know there's you
know 80 percent of the people in the
world
um if we improve their human resource in
each of them to how our human resources
have been tuned up
um wealth on this planet would be like
10 times what it is now a hundred times
what it is now
and it wouldn't all be spent on Hummers
that we spent on Smart stuff like being
generous
wealth spent on being generous is a way
way bigger dividend than wealth stuffed
in vaults Under the Mountain I mean how
many how many books have been telling us
that the act of service is there's like
I mean there's so many uh great
religious texts or even like Tony
Robbins they'll talk about uh serving
others like like when you have something
and it it opens up this thing with
inside of us that that I don't think
we're we're capable of seeing without
experiencing it you know when we're when
we're giving uh when we're teaching uh
yeah I I think it's it's like a little
gift it's a little Little Secret gift
that we're all supposed to lean into I
think is is serving others and when we
and when when we do it in in the in the
way of
um
improving their self-sufficiency
not not only do they look after
themselves they're proud to look after
themselves
oh yeah you know the the the intuition
that people had about the human nature
when we when you created America you
know Adam Smith thought that you once
again he called people men quaintly
men are basically good
right that was the whole fundamental
idea of American constitutional
democracy if we turn good men free only
good things will happen
a problem happened for instance we
created you know legal persons that
weren't men corporations and
corporations aren't good corporations
are utterly neutral they have a
responsibility and their responsibility
is not to be you know corporations don't
get in trouble for [__] other
people's wives
they don't follow morals there is no
they have no obligation to follow morals
right but anyway so at its origin
America
had this extremely positive
um concept of the value of the human
nature now look where it's come to now
if we give a guy 400 bucks during covet
we're going to turn them into a bum
if we give a guy 400 bucks we're gonna
turn him into a bump we're going to make
them you know a lazy uh lazy ass guy for
the rest of his life that's not a very
elevated view of human nature I don't
buy it when we help people ninety
percent of the people we help are going
to run with it and be proud of it and
make something of themselves and get out
there and really you know earn some
money and pay some taxes
and everybody knows that Jacob that 10
of those people are gonna you know [__]
us for the money they're gonna take it
and they're just gonna go you know smoke
weed and drink beer and you know
Stitch everybody else right
but that's not that that does not
exonerate us from our responsibility due
to the 90 percent who actually are going
to take it and do good and and and and
and and honor Adam Smith's idea that
people are actually basically good if we
give them a leg up they're going to go
for it and they're gonna
they're gonna proudly look after
themselves and if if you care about it
and I don't
coming off our tax rolls
oh man really don't get me started
there's a lot of divinaries that I'd
like to get you started on I feel like
we could talk for a long time John
um well so I'm I'm good for two more
hours no I'm just kidding I uh as much
as I wish I could I actually do need to
get I have a um like I said I do do do
DJing as well I have to work uh in a few
hours but I also have a show in
Washington
um this weekend so I've got a lot of DJ
work to do so good for you you're very
active yeah yeah I I try to be I haven't
uh been been out too much in Austin yet
djang
um but I'm uh I'm getting there slowly
but surely trying to figure out exactly
what I want out of this whole DJing
thing and what my long term I I kind of
just loved it and kept doing it and I
never really stopped to think about what
do I really want out of this what do I
want to be when I'm older when it comes
to this performing music art DJing thing
so I'm I'm exploring that it's super
important
Jacob is super important that you know
all my environmental friends say John
how can we like be have any Joy knowing
all these things that we know and I said
you could you know what do you think you
want to conserve all this for and they
said what do you mean that's a stupid
question no no really what do you want
to conserve everything for and you go
you know well everybody knows that yeah
but what and I go you know presumably
it's so that our descendants can enjoy
it too and they go yeah yeah that's sort
of descent is going to say now I got him
right because yeah I said okay so the
important thing is you know the
conserving it is less important the more
important thing is the enjoyment of it
so we have a responsibility to do things
for to our descendants one of them is to
conserve it and the other one is to
teach them how to enjoy it
that's what we got to do to save this
planet is enjoy it so you man get out
there and play some great music and show
people how to dance and then come back
to work hell yeah hell yeah hell yeah
thank you John thank you hey so so I had
one more question I'd like to end the
and try to end the podcast with kind of
like a a strange question or maybe a
question that that's just for this guest
so a little bit of a curveball but
totally nothing weird uh just in in the
music world you're a musician you've
been around music a lot
um I I think about and I've actually
used the sample before from from uh Jim
Morrison
um talking about kind of the future of
music back in the day and he was talking
about how the Medias could be one person
um playing from a tape recorder and kind
of he was predicting DJs in a sense
um I'm curious uh what what you think
where do you see the future of music you
know I I don't know maybe it's in 50
years maybe it's in 60 or whatever where
do you see us going with music what do
you think
our I think our creative our I think our
creative creativity in that respect is
infinite you know give me three chords
and there are an infinite number of
songs that you can make out of them and
you know uh
we're gonna you know as honkies you're
gonna be learning a lot more about
um you know the music that comes from
you know the mountains of China and you
know the deserts of Africa and you know
there's there's really wonderful things
going on musically and Mali now have you
seen some of those guys through some uh
Molly's a Saharan country but they have
this great they love Stratocaster
guitars and they play because you're a
very beautiful tradition so it's it's
gonna go wherever releases the soul and
the people that are playing the music
that's what you know that's what music
is it's like it's an opportunity to take
a hold of uh uh the feeling of uh The
Human Experience you know being a a
vessel of universal Consciousness and
what that feels like and translating it
into in universal language that
everybody can understand and that you
take the feel of that and you turn it
into music and then you play the song
and everybody goes wow that's cool you
bet it's cool man what that is
is turning free in the daytime that part
of us that dreams at night
that's when we be still and and still be
what we do is we're turning on that how
infinitely creative are we in our dreams
definitely infinitely exactly and we are
when we just shut the [__] up yeah it is
right and so I think where music's gonna
go I can't foresee except I know it will
always be going where it moves the
musician the best yeah yeah I love that
man that makes me feel good because I
you know as I again I try to figure out
my spot and what I what I want to give
to the world as a as a musician or what
I can discover and show or what I can
make cooler or whatever and that is true
the the moments where I feel like I'm
actually directing it or maybe I'm I'm
pointing at her I'm touching it or I'm
whatever are those moments where I'm I'm
lost to it I'm in it I'm not thinking
about it I'm in the flow state of of
creating something whether it's uh
writing like a terrible piano song
because I'm not very good yet at all or
it's just you know matching some songs
together
um I really do feel most most like I'm
doing the thing when I'm just just doing
it and not thinking about it just just
existing and bringing forth uh in into
the sound waves only only what I can so
yeah let it be man
hell yeah hell yeah uh John it was so
great to talk to you um can we just so
just so we don't uh leave it out can you
drop uh do you have do you have a
website can you drop the name of your
books just make sure everybody knows
where to find you johnlefaith.com just
spell my name right on your little
finger and then people go to
johnlafave.com there are two books on
there one of them is called allswell
where thou art Earth and why and that's
my sort of theory about where where we
are in space and in time as a species
um it's a bit audacious but uh it's a
it can be Gonzo but it's also very
informative the other one is called good
with money I got somebody else to write
that remember I told you somebody
everybody said to me I should rate this
story it's such an exciting story you
know what about how um you know you turn
rich and billion dollars and flying
around in Jets and all that and going to
jail and all that stuff I didn't really
you know and I I I I I tried to tell
people I tried to do that once but I
tired very quickly of writing sentences
to start with I ended with me and so I
engaged somebody else carry gold to help
write that book and that book is called
good with money and the reason it's
called good with money is because she
talked to all of my financial advisors
and everybody else and he said they all
said this guy's not good with money
so there is a book to be to be written
there after so and that and if anybody's
interested in like the toddry story of
Rags my rags to riches to not Rags
obviously I mean I'm I'm I'm not
ridiculously wealthy anymore but I am
wealthy and so are you but I'm wealthier
than you are
so uh that's John the faith.com on
Facebook you know you can have this John
Lafave on Facebook but there's also um I
I'm on the so-called page and the page
is called thoughtful species so if you
type in thoughtful species that's where
I put in my commentary about um
about uh you know social social
political you know uh human sorts of
things that uh that concern us from day
to day and different ideas I have so
thoughtful species on Facebook yeah I
like that name a lot that's really cool
name thoughtful species that's good
um okay cool well okay John my my
favorite my um my John lafave.com also
has you can listen to all of my music
there it's on all of the uh you know
it's on Spotify and all of that stuff
but you can if you you know you can go
to johnlafave.com and all the stuff I've
ever recorded it's there too as well so
you can scroll through some of that and
see if whatever kind of music you like
there's gonna be something that you
don't like yeah true true cool uh thanks
for having me here Jake it was fantastic
to meet you and I look forward to maybe
uh doing this again if you ever take an
ocean
yeah yeah I I think so man I would I
would like that a lot so again man thank
you for your time thank you for your uh
for your wisdom and uh I really
appreciate it man I'll uh for Jennifer's
of you to say generous but to keep up
the good work yeah thank you man thank
you it'll be uh it might be a couple
weeks until this gets posted um I'll
send you an email when it does though
just so just so you're in the loop it'll
be wonderful thanks all right take care
man listeners take care of yourself love
yourself do some stretching go outside
take a walk breathe some fresh air try
to get uh get with yourself get with
your get away from your thoughts and
just exist for a little bit and drink a
glass of water if you haven't drink any
water fish peace out see you later John
thanks again man and what age should we
learn to have better conversations with
ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
thank you